{
    "id": "2fdd13a8b0c249d592b0343e56fee6c5",
    "title": "Sentence improvement exercise",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "3fff830f605f4e2c8a53190d1e880d9b",
            "title": "Sentence Improvement Exercise",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": ".............................. the airplane took off.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "The fog lifting",
                        "Lifting the fog",
                        "The fog lifted",
                        "The fog having lifted"
                    ],
                    "correct": 3
                },
                {
                    "question": "The accused complained of ......................... by the police.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "tortured",
                        "having been tortured",
                        "being tortured",
                        "having tortured"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "The ocean .........................., they abandoned the voyage.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "was rough",
                        "been rough",
                        "being rough",
                        "is rough"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "We were all happy at ....................... awarded the Nobel Prize.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "Mother Teresa’s being",
                        "Mother Teresa being",
                        "Mother Teresa been"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": ".......................... a rainy day, we had to abandon the match.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "It being",
                        "Being it",
                        "It been",
                        "Been it"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I ....................... the plants. Just after I finished watering it started raining.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "didn't need to water",
                        "hadn't watered",
                        "needn’t have watered",
                        "needn't water"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "id": "25823c2d097b484a8e2179edbf738984",
            "title": "Sentence Improvement Exercise",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "The traveler asked me if I ......................... the way to the nearest inn.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "know",
                        "knew",
                        "had known"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "The doctor ........................ a holiday.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "suggested me to take",
                        "suggested that I should",
                        "suggested to take"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "He was ........................ his rheumatism by a specialist.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "cured of",
                        "cured from",
                        "cured with"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "He threatened that he would shoot me ........................ I didn’t obey his instructions.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "if",
                        "unless",
                        "if not",
                        "whether"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "There is .......................... she broke it.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "no question of denying the fact that",
                        "no denying the fact that",
                        "no denial the fact that"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "id": "f62d9b7112d340a6a4c32569594730c3",
            "title": "Sentence Improvement Exercise",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "In the United States alone more than 40,000 people die every year in car accidents and hundreds of thousands more ..................................... personal and financial injury.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "have suffered",
                        "are suffering",
                        "suffer"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "No matter how efficient, how safe or how .........................................., trains cannot offer the thrill and sense of empowerment provided by the car.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "inexpensive they are",
                        "inexpensive are they",
                        "inexpensive are"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Though their intelligence and ..................................... long lifespan are traits shared by the other great primates, the social behavior and general lifestyle of orangutans are quite different.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "relative",
                        "relatively"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "........................................ made Jack Kerouac the most celebrated member of the Beat Generation were his autobiographical novels and wayward travels.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "What",
                        "That",
                        "Which"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "The Romans perfected the art of building arch bridges and ......................................... them throughout the Roman Empire.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "build",
                        "built",
                        "were building"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}